

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Details

Lisbon, Portugal U.S. +1 (253) 514-2202 PT +351 911 154 215 joshmmerrill@outlook.com

Links

Portfolio

LinkedIn

Github

Skills

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

Bootstrap

React

Figma

Adobe XD

Adobe Illustrator

Adobe Photoshop

Ruby on Rails

PostgresSQL

Object-oriented programming

Profile

I'm a frontend web developer passionate about building responsive websites that people love to use. With 6+ years of experience in the tech, healthcare and aviation industries, I've built a reputation for helping companies achieve their business outcomes by developing digital experiences that increase engagement and customer satisfaction.

I've worked in both corporate environments and agency settings and consider myself to be an avid learner who always seeks out new opportunities that challenge me to grow my skill set.

Employment History

Freelance Web Developer, Self-employed

APRIL 2022 - PRESENT

 Responsible for planning, developing, testing, deploying and maintaining web applications for small business clients using HTML, CSS and Javascript.

Teaching Assistant, Le Wagon, Lisbon, Portugal

APRIL 2022 - PRESENT

 Responsible for helping students grasp key concepts taught during their 10 week boot camp course. Topics supported include: HTML, CSS, Javascript and UI design.

Communications Manager, Alaska Airlines, Seattle, USA

JUNE 2018 - JULY 2021

- Designed and developed user-friendly websites for 20,000+ employees using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Managed internal HR communications and digital content strategy for Alaska Airlines – the fifth largest airline in the United States.
- Advised company leadership on communication strategies and tactics related to sensitive HR topics.

Communications Manager, Sound Physicians, Tacoma, USA

AUGUST 2016 - JUNE 2018

- Oversaw the planning, design and development of the company's internal employee website.
- Managed day-to-day web content strategy and editorial calendar for the entire organization.

Assistant Account Executive, WE Communications, Bellevue, USA

MARCH 2014 - MARCH 2016

- Supported day-to-day public relation activities and media relationships for the Microsoft Surface product team.
- Partnered with Microsoft product managers and engineers to drive positive product reviews and news coverage in tech and consumer media outlets.

Education

Full Stack Web Development Certificate, Le Wagon, Lisbon, Portugal

Bachelor of Science, Strategic Communication, Northern Arizona University, Flagstaff, USA

2013